#### ADEBOLA ALADESURU

211 Samuel Garside De pass Gardens Barking, Essex

**Mobile**: 07534939000, 07506235350 **Email**: boluxyz@yahoo.com

#### PERSONAL STATEMENT

I have a sound IT background and good interpersonal skills, with minimum of three years industry experience, which includes administrative tasks, training, testing, implementing, supporting and managing. I have a very strong background in IT, which allows me to work in all aspect in the IT industry. In addition to proven technical experience in difference projects, I possess excellent leadership, communication and team working skills. I have ability to rapidly accommodate and adapt quickly to various concepts within an organization, which allows me to add value and creativity to teams within short frame of time to achieve success. I currently seek an opportunity and challenges within the IT industry where my knowledge will add value to any Project I have the opportunity to work in.

## KEY SKILLS AND EXPERIENCE

## **Web Application / Website Development**

Significant experience on how to develop systems that connect people or clients to an application within controlled environment that suit business purpose. Also creating platform that internal stockholders use in maintaining developed systems. I have excellent knowledge of information Technology and always willing to learn new software packages to improve my skills further. I am very skilful in using most popular software such as .Net Framework, Visual Basic. Net, JavaScript, JQUERY, React.js, Macromedia Dreamweaver, Macromedia Flash, CSS, MySQL database and PHP, Wordpress, Bootstrap, Photoshop, Microsoft software, GIT

# **Project Management**

End-to-end responsibility for all aspects of project management, including planning, resource mobilisation, execution and risk management, HTML semantics, application structure and Database design.

# Account and relationship management

Managed relationships with clients and vendors, developing business cases for further services/requirements, requesting additional budget and resources. Building a network internally and externally, leveraging relationships with senior management, representing company on project boards and key discussions.

# **Leadership and line management**

Managing and motivating local and remote teams of multinational staff, Responsible for recruiting, inducting, training and developing specialist staff on a global basis leveraging team members' expertise and experience to execute projects to the highest possible standard.

## **Training**

Expertise in organizing, preparing and conducting courses on IT and programming topics, including material development, brochure and hand out creation. Experienced in identifying training needs/gaps for individuals/teams.

# **Administrative Task**

Support colleagues with other administrative duties and face-to-face dealing with client such as responding to queries, day to day data entry and updating information.

## Communication

Outstanding ability to communicate effectively with all key stakeholders, with the credibility and expertise to engage and influence effectively with both internal and external stakeholders, Skilled in analysing and interpreting complex information, and distilling relevant items to stakeholders, identifying trends and potential impact on business critical issues.

## SELECTED CAREER ACHIEVEMENTS

- As a computer instructor and programmer while working for DMSS Computers Institute I
  developed an application that the internal stakeholders of the company, an online exam
  application, which not only setup the exams questions but also mark the questions.
- As one of the IT team staff of New Covenant Christian organisation I developed an intra web
  application the organisation can use in capturing data and record from all key department
  captured data run through a process then processed data then use to make decisions, also all
  Members can use in making request.

## **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

Aug 2016 – Till date Job Title: Web Developer Responsibility: RINGLEY PROPERTY GROUP, LONDON

- Discussing the requirements of a project (the brief) with clients and colleagues with confidence, to present and explain ideas to clients and colleagues
- Develop and maintaining website: building dynamic interface that connect customer or client globally, using XHTML, HTML, CSS, DREAMWEAVER, MYSQL, JAVASCRIPT, JOUERY, PHOTOSHOP, GIT, BOOTSTRAP, REACT.JS
- Creation of deliverable executable code, unit tests, supporting documentation and suggests improvement on existing system.
- Maintaining and Supporting an Application: Responding to client query and provide assistant in building solution
- Creating Data Services: structuring data using SQL
- Deriving the Physical design: determine how the software interface looks like base on the business requirement
- Assist inter related department in diagnosing, troubleshooting and resolving queries
- Support team in continuing to keep a productive culture within the development team.
- Customer care service

# Feb 2014 – 2016 NEW CONVENANT C&S, LONDON Job Title: Software developer / web Developer

**Responsibility:** 

- Stick to the technical strategy dictated by the lead architect for any given solution.
- Develop and maintaining website: building dynamic interface that connect customer or client globally, using XHTML, HTML, CSS, DREAMWEAVER, PHP, JAVASCRIPT, MYSQL, CMS (WORDPRESS)
- Creation of deliverable executable code, unit tests and supporting documentation.
- Maintaining and Supporting an Application: Responding to client query on malfunction of software and provide assistant in building solution
- Support team in continuing to keep a productive culture within the development team.
- Keep abreast of industry trends and use this to contribute to the development of the team and the company capability as a whole.
- Creating Data Services: structuring data using SQL
- Deploying an Application: upload the software to client local system or server

- Deriving the Physical design: determine how the software interface looks like base on the functionality
- Customer care service and administrative tasks

# **EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATION**

Sept 2007- Jan 2011 University of Wales BA (Hons) in Accountancy

Undertook studies in Accountancy with the following modules: Financial Accounting, Law, Management Accounting and Communication Skill, etc.

Jan 2006 - Dec 2006 Computer Powerhouse Institute.
Microsoft Certified Professional (MCP)

Undertook training on how to develop desktop application and Web Designing, and qualified as a Microsoft Certified Professional

Jan 2004 – Dec 2005 Lagos City Computer College Diploma In Computer Science

Studied and qualified for Diploma in Computer Science on the following packages: Microsoft word, Excel, PowerPoint, Access, Macromedia Dreamweaver, macromedia Flash etc.

# **INTEREST**

I enjoy meeting people of different background and travelling; in my personal time I study coding software solution. I love reading and living every day as it comes

## REFEREES

Available on request